{
    "questions": [
        {
            "Question": "What is the best password?",
            "Answers": "kent.SU2018",
            "Format": "M",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "$starwars",
                "Frank2000",
                "bij$223jOIUnKhe",
                "p4$$w0rd"
            ],
            "Why?": "It depends!"
        },
        {
            "Question": "What does CIA stand for?",
            "Answers": "Confidentiality, integrity, availability",
            "Format": "M / I",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "Confidence, Impenetrability, Assurance",
                "Covert Information Access",
                "Cybersecurity Infiltration Analysis"
            ],
            "Why?": "It is a fundamental set of principles for cybersecurity."
        },
        {
            "Question": "What does confidentiality, in the context of cybersecurity, mean?",
            "Answers": "Only authorized parties can access, or even know about the existence of, a particular asset",
            "Format": "M",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "Encrypting all data to make it accessible to everyone",
                "Making information available to anyone who requests it",
                "Ensuring information is kept secret from competitions to gain a competitive advantage"
            ],
            "Why?": "C is roughly equivalent to privacy. Confidentiality measures are designed to prevent sensitive information from unauthorized access attempts."
        },
        {
            "Question": "What does integrity, in the context of cybersecurity, mean?",
            "Answers": "Only authorized parties can access, modify, create and delete asset",
            "Format": "M",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "Integrity means ensuring that assets can be modified, created, and deleted by anyone without restrictions",
                "Integrity is the process of deleting assets to reduce clutter and improve system performance",
                "Integrity is about randomly altering assets to keep them unpredictable"
            ],
            "Why?": "Integrity ensures that data remains accurate, complete, and unaltered."
        },
        {
            "Question": "What does availability, in the context of cybersecurity, mean?",
            "Answers": "Preventing downtime of systems or inability to access data/information",
            "Format": "M",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "Maintaining a strict schedule for system maintenance",
                "Regularly backing up data",
                "Sharing sensitive data"
            ],
            "Why?": "Availability ensures that systems are accessible to authorized users when they need them."
        },
        {
            "Question": "How does authentication best fall into the CIA triad?",
            "Answers": "Integrity?",
            "Format": "I",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "NA"
            ],
            "Why?": "Authentication ensures that only authorized users can access a system or data."
        },
        {
            "Question": "What does 'non-repudiation' mean, in the context of information security?",
            "Answers": "Ability for parties to prove that a message has been sent by a specific person, and received by a specific person.",
            "Format": "M",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "It refers to the process of concealing the identity of both the sender / recipient of a message",
                "It means allowing parties to deny sending / receiving a message without consequence"
            ],
            "Why?": "Means that parties can prove a message was sent by a specific person and received by a specific person, prevents denials of involvement in a message / transactions. This is usually achieved through digital signatures / cryptographic methods."
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the best definition of a vulnerability?",
            "Answers": "A weakness or flaw in a system, application, or network that can be exploited by malicious actors to compromise the confidentiality, integrity, or availability of data or systems",
            "Format": "M",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "A vulnerability refers to the physical damage caused by external factors such as natural disasters or accidents that disrupt the normal functioning of a system",
                "A vulnerability is any software feature that enhances the performance of a system or application but may not adhere to certain industry standards"
            ],
            "Why?": "Understanding vulnerabilities in the context of a quiz system is crucial for implementing robust security measures."
        },
        {
            "Question": "In a corporate network, if an employee receives an email with a suspicious attachment and opens it, what type of threat is this?",
            "Answers": "Malware",
            "Format": "I",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "Malware attack"
            ],
            "Why?": "When an employee unknowingly opens an email attachment that is suspicious, it can potentially introduce malware into the network. Malware is malicious software designed to compromise security of the system."
        },

        {
            "Question": "A tech company is trying to secure its sensitive data from unauthorized data. What is an essential measure it should consider to protect its IP?",
            "Answers": "Encryption",
            "Format": "M",
            "Alt Answers": [
               "Copyright",
               "Open Access",
               "Passwords"
            ],
            "Why?": "Encryption is an essential measure for protecting IP because it involves encoding the information in such a way that only authorized parties can access it,encryption means making the data unreadable to anyone without the ability to decrypt it."
        },

        {
            "Question:": "A cybersecurity professional is tasked with identifying critical vulnerabilities within their organization. According to the lecture, what is an example of a (potential) asset?",
            "Answers": "Money",
            "Format": "I",
            "Alt Answers": [
                "Informaton",
                "Physical possessions",
                "Facilities",
                "People",
                "Reputation",
                "Intangibles"
            ],
            "Why?": "Assets are anything of value to an organization. They can be tangible or intangible, and can include information, physical possessions, facilities, people, reputation, and more."
        }
    ]
}
